<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asim Unmesh on Asim Unmesh</title>
    <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asim Unmesh on Asim Unmesh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy Asim Unmesh; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>GRE : A Guide for a 328ish Score</title>
      <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/post/gre-a-hacky-guide-for-a-328ish-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:35:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aunmesh.github.io/post/gre-a-hacky-guide-for-a-328ish-score/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; This manuscript is written in the form of an interview. Two reasons:&lt;br&gt;
1. Interviews are structured. You can spot a relevant question and read the answer.&lt;br&gt;
2. It makes me go through a &lt;strong&gt;self supervised training for interviews&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-was-your-gre-and-when-did-you-start-preparing-for-it&#34;&gt;When was your GRE and when did you start preparing for it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My GRE was on 5th of July. I started preparing for it around 20th of May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-was-your-score&#34;&gt;What was your score?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I scored 160 in Verbal Section, 168 in Quant and 4 in analytical writing skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-had-2-weeks-for-preparation-do-you-think-it-was-enough-for-you&#34;&gt;You had 2 weeks for preparation. Do you think it was enough for you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I think it was enough for me. If I would have gotten more time, it could have improved my score. But keeping in mind that giving too much time for GRE would have hampered my other facets of my academics I think I gave GRE exactly the time and energy it needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;okay-would-you-recommend-everyone-else-a-2-week-timeframe-or-it-depends&#34;&gt;Okay, would you recommend everyone else a 2 week timeframe or it depends?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it depends. I have heard of people who just practiced for 2 days and scored 338. Some people practiced for a lot more but still couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the score they wanted. You obviously need to judge yourself well and then select the timeframe you need. I would say most people I came across need time from 2 months to 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;which-section-was-easier-one-and-which-one-was-harder-one-for-you&#34;&gt;Which section was easier one and which one was harder one for you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me Quant was the easier. Although I couldn&amp;rsquo;t score full marks, but still I would say it was very comfortable. Verbal was the more complicated one for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-do-you-say-verbal-was-complicated-for-you&#34;&gt;Why do you say Verbal was &amp;ldquo;Complicated&amp;rdquo; for you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt I could do well in Verbal before I started the preparation. But into my preparations I realised this was not so straightforward. It depended on a lot of things. There were multiple stages of preparation which could not be done randomly. As in they needed to be done in an order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-will-you-breakup-your-stages-for-preparation-of-the-verbal-section&#34;&gt;How will you breakup your &amp;ldquo;stages&amp;rdquo; for preparation of the verbal section?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will break them up as:&lt;br&gt;
1. Vocabulary building.&lt;br&gt;
2. More Vocabulary building.&lt;br&gt;
3. Comprehension Practice.&lt;br&gt;
4. Multiple Full Verbal Section tests.&lt;br&gt;
5. Analyzing your errors in the tests and improving upon them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-see-that-you-have-stressed-upon-vocabulary-building-here-can-you-expand-on-the-reasons&#34;&gt;I see that you have stressed upon vocabulary building here. Can you expand on the reasons?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, for starters lets say that without vocabulary you would be clueless and confused and underconfident in general regarding the GRE verbal section. Confidence is a must here, as well as clarity. Without vocabulary you will not be able to understand the comprehensions, sentences etc. You would be confused about the options given in the answers. Also having a sound vocabulary fetches you marks directly as GRE asks questions like fill the most appropriate word. So I would say that vocabulary is the backbone of your GRE Verbal Section preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-will-you-recommend-building-vocabulary-for-gre&#34;&gt;How will you recommend building vocabulary for GRE?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two Words - Magoosh Flashcards&lt;/strong&gt;. Magoosh Flashcards all the way. For the readers, please dont bother yourself with any other source. I am not advertising for Magoosh, but sticking to it will be efficient as well as thorough for your preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-comprehension-practice-especially-and-not-practice-of-other-types-of-questions-asked-in-the-verbal-section&#34;&gt;Why comprehension practice especially, and not practice of other types of questions asked in the Verbal Section?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is because the other types of questions which will be asked can be easily answered if you have a sound knowledge of vocabulary. You don&amp;rsquo;t need anything extra. Comprehensions are more trickier though. They require you to have a handle on few skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-skills-for-comprehensions&#34;&gt;What skills (for comprehensions)?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all it requires concentration. You need to go through 2-3 or sometimes even 4 paragraphs of information. This inforamtion seems ambiguous as you begin to read. This is because you start without a heading.  So you are clueless as to what the comprehension is even about. So you need to be focused, and process information well. Secondly, you must not absolutely make any assumptions. We have a habit of making a lot of assumptions when we read. GRE asks questions an what is written there in the passage, not how you have read it in your head. So you must teach yourself to objectively read&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation of Evolution of Society</title>
      <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/publication/simulation-of-evolution-of-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 18:38:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aunmesh.github.io/publication/simulation-of-evolution-of-society/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surfnet Generating 3D Shape Surfaces Using Deep Residual Networks</title>
      <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/publication/surfnet-generating-3d-shape-surfaces-using-deep-residual-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aunmesh.github.io/publication/surfnet-generating-3d-shape-surfaces-using-deep-residual-networks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
