<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asim Unmesh on Asim Unmesh</title>
    <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asim Unmesh on Asim Unmesh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy Asim Unmesh; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Monty Hall Problem : Way of the Bayesian</title>
      <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/post/monty-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 04:52:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aunmesh.github.io/post/monty-hall/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Monty Hall Problem is famous problem in probability.  It is not only famous, but also important. This problem tests how good we understand probability. One of its appearence in popular culture is in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zr_xWfThjJ0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;scene&lt;/a&gt; of &amp;ldquo;21&amp;rdquo; movie. Please ignore, the explanation given there. But I bet you can&amp;rsquo;t ignore the amazing Kevin Spacey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;So, what is the problem?
Problem statement(taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monty_Hall_problem&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;):
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suppose you&amp;rsquo;re on a game show, and you&amp;rsquo;re given the choice of three doors: Behind one door is a car; behind the others, goats. You pick a door, say No. 1, and the host, who goes by the name Monty, knows what&amp;rsquo;s behind the doors. He opens another door, say No. 3, which has a goat. He then says to you, &amp;ldquo;Do you want to pick door No. 2?&amp;rdquo; Is it to your advantage to switch your choice?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first became acquainted with this problem during an internship interview. I had just started my sophomore year in college. This was the first problem interviewer asked me. I tried to think, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand why should we even bother to revise. Finally, I decided that it was a trick question, and said that no we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. I made up a faulty reasoning to support my claim. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t given an offer, and I place the blame on this wretched problem.(Hence, the blog post :P). In this post, a Bayesian Reasoning for the problem is presented along with an intuitive reason for the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-why-should-we-even-bother-to-switch-br&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why? Why should we even bother to switch?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to address this &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; before proceeding any further. We need to bother simply because there is a change in information. Extra information has been made available by Monty. That information is the presence of a goat behind the third door. This information was not there when we picked door 1. At the start, there was the possibility, that the car could be behind the 3rd door. Now we know for sure that it is not the case. Hence, we need to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enter-probability&#34;&gt;Enter Probability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probability theory is an amazing part of Mathematics. One of the reasons it is so amazing is because it has enabled a rational procedure for making guesses. I will say that again - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Rational Guess Work&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. And thus, if we are to be smart here, and make rational choices, we need to follow Probability Theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-answer&#34;&gt;The Answer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets not stand on ceremony here and reveal the answer. The answer is - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, it is in our interest to switch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. In fact, the probability of us winning if we switch is &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;, while if we don&amp;rsquo;t is just &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;Counter-intuitive? Yes? No? For me it was. It was very counter-intuitive that we should switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-faulty-argument-that-we-should-not-switch&#34;&gt;A faulty argument that we should not switch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Note: We represent Car by &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt; and Goat by &lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
A faulty argument using probability theory proceeds as follow:
&lt;br&gt;Upon revelation, by Monty, there is now a 50-50 chance of our door having the car. This is because our door can now have either car or goat. And since only goat is left, the possibilities are: &lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;C G&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;G C&lt;/strong&gt; (The first letter in the configuration stands for what is behind the first door and so on). Hence there is &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; probability for each configuration, and so making a switch does not help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;where-s-the-fault&#34;&gt;Where&amp;rsquo;s the fault?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fault is in assuming that both these configurations are equi-probable. That is, the possibility that one can occur is same as the other. However, that is not the case. It will become clear later, as to why that is not the case. But, the major reason this mistake is committed is because history is ignored. The past information is compltely ignored and only the current possibilities are consulted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possible configurations according to the past information:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;C G G&lt;/strong&gt; (config 1) , &lt;strong&gt;G C G&lt;/strong&gt;(config 2) , &lt;strong&gt;G G C&lt;/strong&gt;(config 3)
&lt;br&gt; All of these are equiprobable hence each of the configurations probability is &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-bayesian-reasoning&#34;&gt;A Bayesian Reasoning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Reasonings given will be best followed by using a pen and a notebook]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One realises, if they look at the problem carefully, is that the probability of door 1 having a car hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed. Before revelation proability that door 1 has Car was &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;. Post revelation the probability still remains &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;( This is because pre revelation, door 1 could either have a car, or 1st goat or 2nd goat. Hence &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; probability .Post revelation we have seen that configuration &lt;strong&gt;C G G&lt;/strong&gt; has &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; probability and configuration &lt;strong&gt;G C G&lt;/strong&gt; has &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; probability. So, post revelation, probability of door 1 having a car is same as the probability of &lt;strong&gt;C G G&lt;/strong&gt; configuration, or &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is remarkable.
We will see why this happens, as we argue that we should switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I chose door 1, I had placed my belief on &lt;em&gt;config 1&lt;/em&gt;. So, when Monty opened door 3 and showed me a goat, should I be surprised? If I should be surprised, then by how much should I be surprised? Since I chose &lt;em&gt;config 1&lt;/em&gt;, I hoped the Car to be in the first door and goats behind the other 2 doors. Thus, if I assume &lt;em&gt;config 1&lt;/em&gt; to be the case, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised at all that the goat is behind door 3.&lt;br&gt; However, I &lt;strong&gt;should be surprised&lt;/strong&gt;. This is not because of the goats or cars, but because of what Monty did. Monty revealed door 3, rather than door 2. Why?  &lt;br&gt;How probable is this(Monty revealing door 2 rather than door 3). It&amp;rsquo;s probability is &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (if we assume &lt;em&gt;config 1&lt;/em&gt; to be true).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Let&amp;rsquo;s revisit Bayes rule:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{align}
 P(A \mid B) = \frac{P(B \mid A) \, P(A)}{P(B)}
\end{align}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;or in our case &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{align}
\hspace{-80pt}P(Car\ behind\ door\ 1 \mid what\ happened) = \frac{P(what\ happened | Car\ behind\ door\ 1) * P(Car\ behind\ door\ 1)}{P(what\ happened)}
\end{align}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Note: When conditioning information is not there, we have to condition with the information we had before the revelation]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have ascertained that P(what happened | Car behind door 1) = &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;Now what is P( what happened)? We have to find the probability of &amp;ldquo;What happened&amp;rdquo; given our prior knowledge, that is at the beginning of the game. Or more clearly, what is the probability that I would have chosen door 1, and then Monty would have revealed door 3 to be having a goat?
&lt;br&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s find out this probability using 3 disjoint events. That is 3 disjoint configurations. &amp;ldquo;What happened&amp;rdquo;, could not have happened if &lt;em&gt;config 3&lt;/em&gt; was the case. &amp;ldquo;What happened&amp;rdquo; could have happened with 1 probability if &lt;em&gt;config 2&lt;/em&gt; was the case. However, &lt;em&gt;config 2&lt;/em&gt; has &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; probability. What happened could have happened with &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; probability if &lt;em&gt;config 1&lt;/em&gt; were the case, however, &lt;em&gt;config 1&lt;/em&gt; itself has &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; probability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence net probability of &amp;ldquo;What happened&amp;rdquo; given our prior beliefs is &lt;br&gt;
(&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)*(&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) + 1 * (&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) = &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we see that&lt;br /&gt;
\begin{align}
P(what\ happened \mid Car\ behind\ door\ 1) = P(what\ happened).
\end{align}
&lt;br&gt; They cancel out on RHS of (2) and we are left with:&lt;br&gt;
\begin{align}
P(Car\ behind\ door\ 1 \mid what\ happened) = P(Car\ behind\ door\ 1)
\end{align}
&lt;br&gt;So, now we know why the probability stays the same even after revelation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{align}
\hspace{-110pt}P( Car\ behind\ door\ 1 \mid what\ happened) + P( Car\ behind\ door 2 \mid what\ happened) + P( Car\ behind\ door\ 3 \mid what\ happened) = 1.
\end{align}
But,
\begin{align}
P( Car\ behind\ door\ 3 \mid what\ happened) = 0
\end{align}
So, P( Car behind door 2 | what happened) = &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence we should switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;intuitively-why-switching-is-better-taken-from-betterexplained-https-betterexplained-com-articles-understanding-the-monty-hall-problem&#34;&gt;Intuitively why switching is better [taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://betterexplained.com/articles/understanding-the-monty-hall-problem/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;betterexplained&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see why removing doors makes switching attractive. Instead of the regular game, imagine this variant:&lt;br&gt;
1. There are 100 doors to pick from in the beginning&lt;br&gt;
2. You pick one door&lt;br&gt;
* Monty looks at the 99 others, finds the goats, and opens all but 1&lt;br&gt;
Do you stick with your original door (&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;100&lt;/sub&gt;), or the other door, which was filtered from 99?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit clearer: Monty is taking a set of 99 choices and improving them by removing 98 goats. When he’s done, he has the top door out of 99 for you to pick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your decision: Do you want a random door out of 100 (initial guess) or the best door out of 99? Said another way, do you want 1 random chance or the best of 99 random chances?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re starting to see why Monty’s actions help us. He’s letting us choose between a generic, random choice and a curated, filtered choice. Filtered is better.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked at the Monty Hall problem, important points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always account for information change.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While assigning probabilities, always check if the events are equiprobable or not.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayesian approach is a principled approach for posterior inference(updating belief after seeing new information). We just need to apply it properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;asides&#34;&gt;Asides&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For another puzzle in probability basics see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Two_envelopes_problem&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Two Envelopes Problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayesian approach fits nicely into machine learning. A model needs to update its belief accordingly, upon seeing new data. This is called the problem of posterior inference.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also enables us to have a measure of uncertainty in our beliefs. This is more powerful than just knowing which is the more suitable choice.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;See this nature &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature14541&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; for an intro to Probabilistic Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approximate Inference for MetaLDA using SGRLD </title>
      <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/project/approxmetalda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 17:20:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aunmesh.github.io/project/approxmetalda/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRE : A Guide for a 328ish Score</title>
      <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/post/gre-a-hacky-guide-for-a-328ish-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:35:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aunmesh.github.io/post/gre-a-hacky-guide-for-a-328ish-score/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; This post is written in the form of an interview. Reasons* at the end
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-was-your-gre-and-when-did-you-start-preparing-for-it&#34;&gt;When was your GRE and when did you start preparing for it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My GRE was on 5th of July. I started preparing for it around 20th of June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-was-your-score&#34;&gt;What was your score?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I scored &lt;sup&gt;160&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;170&lt;/sub&gt; in Verbal Section, &lt;sup&gt;168&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;170&lt;/sub&gt; in Quantitative Section and &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt; in Analytical Writing Skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-had-2-weeks-for-preparation-do-you-think-it-was-enough-for-you&#34;&gt;You had 2 weeks for preparation. Do you think it was enough for you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I think it was enough for me. If I would have gotten more time, it could have improved my score. But keeping in mind that giving too much time for GRE would have hampered other areas of my pursuits I think I gave GRE exactly the time and energy it needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;okay-would-you-recommend-a-2-week-timeframe-or-it-depends&#34;&gt;Okay, would you recommend a 2 week timeframe or it depends?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it depends. I have heard of people who just practiced for 2 days and scored 338. Some people practiced for a lot more but still couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the score they wanted. You obviously need to judge yourself well and then select the timeframe you need. Most people I came across need time from 2 months to 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;which-section-was-easier-one-and-which-one-was-harder-one-for-you&#34;&gt;Which section was easier one and which one was harder one for you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me Quant was the easier. Although I couldn&amp;rsquo;t score full marks, but still I would say that it was comfortable. Verbal was the more complicated one for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-do-you-say-verbal-was-complicated-for-you&#34;&gt;Why do you say Verbal was &amp;ldquo;Complicated&amp;rdquo; for you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt I could do well in Verbal before I started preparing. But into my preparations I realised that this was not so straightforward. It depended on a lot of things. There were multiple stages of preparation which could not be done randomly. They needed to be done in an order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-will-you-breakup-your-stages-for-preparing-for-the-verbal-section&#34;&gt;How will you breakup your &amp;ldquo;stages&amp;rdquo; for preparing for the verbal section?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will break them up as:&lt;br&gt;
1. Vocabulary building.&lt;br&gt;
2. More Vocabulary building.&lt;br&gt;
3. Comprehension Practice.&lt;br&gt;
4. Giving multiple full Verbal Section tests.&lt;br&gt;
5. Analyzing your errors in the tests and improving upon them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-see-that-you-have-stressed-upon-vocabulary-building-here-can-you-expand-on-the-reasons&#34;&gt;I see that you have stressed upon vocabulary building here. Can you expand on the reasons?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, for starters lets say that without vocabulary you would be clueless and confused and underconfident in general regarding the GRE verbal section. Confidence is a must here, as well as clarity. Without vocabulary you will not be able to understand the comprehensions, sentences etc. You would be confused about the options given in the answers. Also having a sound vocabulary fetches you marks directly as GRE asks questions like fill the most appropriate word. So I would say that vocabulary is the backbone of your GRE Verbal Section preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-will-you-recommend-building-vocabulary-for-gre&#34;&gt;How will you recommend building vocabulary for GRE?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two Words - &lt;strong&gt;Magoosh Flashcards&lt;/strong&gt;. Magoosh Flashcards all the way. Please dont bother yourself with any other source. I am not advertising for Magoosh, but sticking to it will be efficient as well as being thorough with your preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-comprehension-practice-especially-and-not-practicing-other-types-of-questions-asked-in-the-verbal-section&#34;&gt;Why comprehension practice especially, and not practicing other types of questions asked in the Verbal Section?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you have to practice them too. However other types of questions which will be asked can be easily answered if you have a sound knowledge of vocabulary. You don&amp;rsquo;t need anything extra. Comprehensions are more trickier though. They require you to have a handle on a few skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-skills-for-comprehensions&#34;&gt;What skills (for comprehensions)?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all it requires concentration. You need to go through 2-3 or sometimes even 4 paragraphs of information. This inforamtion seems ambiguous as you begin to read. This is because you start without a heading.  So you are clueless as to what the comprehension is even about. Hence you need to be focused, and process information well.&lt;br&gt; Secondly, you should absolutely not make any assumptions. We have a habit of making a lot of assumptions when we read. GRE asks questions on what is written there in the passage, not how you have read it in your head. So you must teach yourself to objectively read without assuming anything even subconsciously.&lt;br&gt;
Thirdly,  you will need to link information well. Based on the question they are asking, you will have to filter the options by linking the information scattered across the passage. Elimination is a very sound strategy here. But the key here is eliminating with a firm reasoning you feel confident about.&lt;br&gt;
Lastly you need to be able to read at speed, as the time is limited in GRE. Reading at speed is tricky, but maintaining speed while doing the above said things is trickier. So, throttle up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;any-hacks-you-used-for-comprehensions&#34;&gt;Any hacks you used (for comprehensions)?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I came across one on some youtube video where a girl was talking about her GRE. The questions for a comprehension are usually asked in the order of the paragraphs. Its not a hard and fast rule, but &amp;ldquo;usually&amp;rdquo;. So if there are a lot of paragraphs you can try answering a question after you have read one paragraph instead of reading the whole passage.&lt;br&gt; Also another habit which I developed was, reading all the questions related to one passage, before reading the passage. This made me aware of the information to look for, and I could immediately identify the important bits when I saw them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;that-was-insightful-practice-must-be-the-key-here-to-develop-these-habits-or-skills&#34;&gt;That was insightful. Practice must be the key here to develop these habits or skills?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes ,absolutely. As with everything else, deliberate and puposeful practice is a must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-did-you-practice-these-full-verbal-section-tests-from&#34;&gt;Where did you practice these full verbal section tests from?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I practiced them from the hardcopy of Kaplan GRE Guide , as well as from their software which gives us 10 full practice tests for each section. That was very helpful, as it helped me circumvent the need for giving a full test, and just focus on section wise improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;would-you-recommend-section-wise-tests-over-full-gre-test&#34;&gt;Would you recommend section wise tests over full GRE test?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I would. This is because GRE tests are structured section wise. If you are confident that sitting in an exam for some duration, say 4-5 hours is not a problem for you, then you can absolutely give only section wise tests and still get away with not giving any full test. A fun fact - I got away too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;okay-i-think-we-covered-the-verbal-section-there-what-about-the-quant-section-did-you-have-practice&#34;&gt;Okay, I think we covered the verbal section there. What about the Quant section? Did you have practice?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, absolutely. It is not wise to be overconfident. I practiced 5 section tests of Quant and also revised the formulas etc. well before the exam. They were mostly elementary, but doing so helps with your confidence going into the exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;any-important-points-for-quant-section&#34;&gt;Any important points for Quant section?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah. Firstly don&amp;rsquo;t be lethargic. Solve questions with speed and accuracy. If you get stuck in some question, mark it and leave it after spending at most 90 seconds on it. If you complete one pass in say 25 minutes, you will still be left with 10 minutes to revisit those questions. I will say that a fast and accurate first pass over the whole section is important for quant section. Also make use of the mark and review button well. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to use them, but also don&amp;rsquo;t use them too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-about-the-analytical-writing-section-did-you-practice-it&#34;&gt;What about the analytical writing section? Did you practice it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not devote time as much as I would have liked for analytical writing. I was somewhat confident in my ability to write. But I was not that confident on how to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-do-you-mean-by-how-to-write&#34;&gt;What do you mean by &amp;ldquo;how to write&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean what structure did GRE expect. How the essay had to be organized. Also what were they looking for in &amp;ldquo;analyze the argument&amp;rdquo; essay and what different were they looking for in the issue based essays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-did-you-prepare-for-it-analytical-writing-section-if-you-didn-t-practice-writing-them&#34;&gt;How did you prepare for it (analytical writing section)? If you didn&amp;rsquo;t practice writing them?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple, I read up 3-4 sample essays for each of the &amp;ldquo;analyze an argument&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;issue based&amp;rdquo; essay types. They were essays which were scored &lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;, so I got a good understanding of how to write the essay. Also, the Kaplan people had mentioned the steps on how to go about writing the essays. They were mostly about collecting your points before writing, introducing in first para, giving one para for one point and not mixing up the points between the paras(i.e. to keep one point to one para only). Finally they talked about concluding it. Please take note that issue based essays and argument based essays are very different and you need to understand how they differ. You must comprehend their nuances and subtleties. ( You can look up the templates for argument based essays &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaptest.com/study/gre/how-to-structure-the-gre-argument-essay/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and issue based essays &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaptest.com/gre/gre-issue-essay&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. ) Although, I feel that I should have practiced more, but doing the above things helped me get away with zero writing practice and get a &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt; score. So I feel that doing that above said things is a must, whether or not you actually practice writing the essays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;anything-for-test-day&#34;&gt;Anything for test day?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep revising the vocab until say 3 hrs before the test. Those things keep slipping away. If you are not confident about the quant section, revise their formulas too. Keep some sort of self-made notes, so that revision is quick and efficient.
Remeber to bring some chocolate or a source of quick glucose. It helps you with energy levels required to maintain concentration and efficiency. Finally, be at ease, because no matter what, you will be okay!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[End]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
*Reasons for writing this post as an interview:&lt;br&gt;
1. Interviews are structured. You can spot a relevant question and read the answer. &lt;br&gt;
2. It makes me go through a self supervised training for interviews. More on self supervision &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exforsys.com/career-center/self-supervision/self-supervision-introduction.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. For a Machine Learning angle to self supervision, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/toyota-ai-ventures/self-supervised-learning-a-key-to-unlocking-self-driving-cars-408b7a6fd3bd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;And why do we fall Bruce?&amp;rdquo; &lt;br&gt; -Thomas Wayne&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation of Evolution of Society</title>
      <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/publication/simulation-of-evolution-of-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 18:38:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aunmesh.github.io/publication/simulation-of-evolution-of-society/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surfnet Generating 3D Shape Surfaces Using Deep Residual Networks</title>
      <link>https://aunmesh.github.io/publication/surfnet-generating-3d-shape-surfaces-using-deep-residual-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aunmesh.github.io/publication/surfnet-generating-3d-shape-surfaces-using-deep-residual-networks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
